(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(SQUAWKS)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
BECKETT: Range me.
PAPICH: Three to five
on the legs.
(VEHICLES APPROACHING)
BECKETT: They're coming.
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
BECKETT: Scan them.
Find Cabrera.
PAPICH: At the Jeep.
Designer sunglasses.
BECKETT: You sure that's him?
PAPICH: I'm reading his rank
and name tag.
He's moving.
BECKETT: Six-5-0. Range me.
PAPICH: Range correct, 6-5-0.
BECKETT: When he clears
the civilians
he's mine.
(SCREAMING AND SHOUTING)
(GUNS FIRING)
(GUNS FIRING CONTINUOUSLY)
(GUNFIRE CEASES)
Anything?
Nothing.
Two more hours.
Damn, I hate
the downtime.
Well, you have a leave
coming up, don't you?
Yeah.
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
(HELICOPTER NEARING)
That can't be our extraction.
Ah, those dipshits.
I told them no daylight.
Should I pop smoke?
No. Come on.
Let's get out of here
before those
cheesedicks page us
over the P.A. System.
(HELICOPTER NEARING)
Come on! Come on!
(GUNSHOT FIRING)
(GUNS FIRING CONTINUOUSLY)
You're fucking crazy!
He's gone down!
Wait!
Come back here!
Beckett!
(GUN FIRING CONTINUOUSLY)
Why didn't you let
the door gunner
sweep it out first?
My spotter is dead because
you assholes got here early.
I asked for
a night extraction.
I ought to
leave you out there,
you son of a bitch.
We'll be needing
both of those, Gunny.
He only needs one.
(AUTOMATIC GUN FIRING)
Colonel Weymuth,
this is Richard Miller.
He'll be our man
in Panama.
Mr. Miller.
Heard a lot about you.
Come on,
sit down.
Intelligence indicates
there is a major coup
planned for election day
in Panama.
Colombian drug lord,
Raul Ochoa
is bankrolling it.
His plan is to put in
rebel general,
Miguel Alvarez,
in power.
We have less
than one week
to prevent that.
With Alvarez
running the country
Ochoa could very easily
gain access to
the Panama Canal.
We have only one shot
at Alvarez
and it is absolutely critical
that we eliminate the general
prior to next week's
elections.
Now, this operation won't bear
congressional scrutiny.
It must be
completely covert.
You won't be getting
a medal for this, Richard,
but there will be
other tangible benefits.
The first one's Alvarez.
Most recent photo
was taken ten days ago.
The ponytail's Ochoa.
Ochoa is never seen
outside of Colombia.
That's Alvarez's  hacienda.
That's where you'll find him.
That's your shooter.
Master Gunnery Sergeant
Thomas Beckett.
He's the Marine
Corps' top man.
He's logged more time
in the jungle
than any other sniper.
On this particular mission
your function
is to be his spotter.
Mr. Miller, should anything
happen to Beckett
your duty would be
to eliminate Alvarez
personally.
Don't worry about
having to shoot
anybody, Richard.
Beckett is the best.
I'm sure
it wouldn't come to that.
I may not have any kills
but I have had
men in my sights.
Good.
We're giving you rank
on this one, G.S. Nine.
The mission
is under your command.
It's your
responsibility.
Good luck, Richard.
Consider it done.
Gentlemen.
Uh, Miller...
One last thing.
This assignment
is critical.
If at any point
Beckett becomes
a liability
or he endangers
this mission's
covert status
you're going to have
to take him out.
(RADIO PLAYING
ROCK AND ROLL)
Senor, viste, viste.
Buy one.
MAN:  The embassy is pleased.
They'll mark Cabrera
"Confirmed kill, classified"
on your service jacket.
We're very sorry
about your spotter.
BECKETT:
It was a rebel sniper
that got Papich.
He's still out there.
You know, Washington
is really excited
about these upcoming
elections.
Why is that, sir?
Our policy
is to see this country
have a freely elected
government.
That could happen
in a couple of months.
You know it will be
the usual damned thing.
People will be
too scared to vote.
Well...
Whatever you and I
may think, Tom,
Washington feels
this is the right time
to go after
the rebel leadership.
You're sending it
my way, sir?
Yes, I am.
We're getting
a little long in the tooth
for this kind of thing, Tom,
but I figure this
would make a great capper
for a fine career.
Now the National
Security Council
is sending
a guy along
to help a shooter.
He's coming
with full plans.
A civilian?
Just hold on.
Wait a minute.
Take a look.
The army shooting team,
plucked him right
out of ROTC.
He took a silver
in the '88 Olympics.
After his discharge,
the NSC Assigned him
to a Washington, D.C.
SWAT team.
It's all in there.
Take a look.
Has he ever been
in a jungle?
Does he speak
any Spanish?
This is not
a matter of choice.
Just trust me.
Anybody the NSC Sends
down here is going to be
fully qualified.
(HUMMING)
Hey, yo!
What do you got
in there, anyway?
A bassoon.
With the Marine Corps
band, right?
Exactly.
New psy-ops strategy.
We're going to
charm the rebels
like snakes.
Whip a charm on this.
Shit, Ripoly!
Whip a charm.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, take a swig.
It'll burn through
that frost you got.
Ripoly!
Give me your
battle dressing.
battle dressing!
Jesus Christ.
We got wounded.
Jesus Christ!
Baker, stand by,
stand by.
Shit, we're hit!
Where is he?
Anyone got a visual?
There he is. Kill him!
On your side. Get him.
You'll get us all killed.
Take it down.
For Christ's sake,
take it down.
He's shooting at us.
Godammit! Use your
fucking weapon!
Look out.
(SCREAMING)
We're gonna die!
Oh, God,
we're gonna die!
(SCREAMING)
SOLDIER: Kill him.
Get us out of here.
Come on. There he is.
Get him!
Come on, let's go!
Come on!
(GROANS)
(GROANING)
Jesus Christ!
You got him
with a sniper rifle.
Yeah.
SOLDIERS:
* Just to make Panama green
* Left, right, yay-o
* Left, right, yay-o... *
How about a game?
I got a game.
Can I get a beer?
Coming up.
Hey.
So, you're going down south,
towards the border?
I'm not at liberty
to discuss my mission.
How do you feel
about hanging on
a charm bracelet?
Come again?
You better take a good
look at Master Beckett's
dog tag collection.
Got any money?
Yeah, I'll play
for money.
I said I already
got a game.
I'm talking about holding
onto your cash
while you're
out in the jungle.
Better do it, man.
Those rebels can fund
a whole offensive
on what they take off you.
I'm ready
for a game now.
He doesn't have time
for a game.
G.S. Nine Miller?
A lot of attitude
around here.
Welcome to marine world.
Those people thought
you were a sniper.
It's an outcast
profession.
They always go out
in platoon strength.
We go out in pairs.
Sometimes alone.
Their idea of combat
is tearing up the countryside
with heavy artillery
and millions of rounds.
We'll wait days
for one shot, one kill.
Well...
I guess it's a different
version of war.
There's a lot of them
and just a few of us.
MILLER: What's that?
Sometimes these shells
get nicks and burrs
on them.
This little son of a bitch
will take your head off
at 1,000 yards.
Have you had
a chance to look over
our operations plan?
Yeah, I have, but I want
to study it a little more.
Forget the specifics.
How about an overview?
We'll get to that later.
I have a few things
I have to do.
See you at 5.0, 500.
Having had.
Having had what?
Breakfast.
Miller.
This is Corporal Papich's
gillie suit.
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
Is that our ride?
BECKETT:
No. That's our ride.
I thought this was
a deep jungle insertion.
Don't we do that
by chopper?
Yeah, that's
the usual S.O.P.
But those asshole
rudderheads at battalion...
They've fucked with me
one time too many.
We're going to have
to walk it in.
(MEN SINGING IN SPANISH)
My fiancée.
You married?
What's that?
Got it out
of a catalog
when I was with
D.C. Swat.
We called it
"Gucci-flage."
You're going
to wear that?
Yeah.
Let me see it.
Nice shot.
Ain't no room
for Peter Pan on this hunt.
You wear Corporal Papich's
tree togs that I gave you.
What the hell are those for?
Respect.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
MILLER:
I still think a chopper
insertion would have made
a hell of a lot more sense.
By the way, that was
a hell of a shot you made
from a chopper.
That's the sort of thing
myths are made of.
Yeah, it was pretty unreal.
Yeah.
Roll down
your sleeves, Miller.
We're going in the bush.
(CHUCKLES)
What?
What, I missed a spot?
Come on, on your feet.
I had a lot
of swat training,
all right?
Urban anti-terrorist tactics.
I've never actually
done a creep.
The army ever put you
in the jungle?
If you call deepest, darkest
North Carolina a jungle, yeah.
You want to
survive this, right?
One answer to that.
If you do as I tell you
to the letter,
I think you
got a chance.
Whoa, okay? Hold on.
You may have
a hell of a lot more
experience than I do,
but with all
due respect, Gunny,
this mission is NSC.
Meaning, I still have rank,
whether you see it or not.
Sorry, but I don't
have to take orders
from you.
Fair enough.
You want to take point?
You're doing fine.
I got it.
You sure?
Yeah. Go ahead.
Argh!
Goddamn!
You all right, son?
Yeah.
Son of a bitch!
Hey...
Relax. You did okay.
Oh, thanks.
Is there a wrong
way to fall down
a fucking mountain?
Your weapon, Miller.
It's your life.
You knew that,
and you saved it.
You're learning, son.
Beckett.
Hmm?
Our drop point
from the railway
was east.
Now, now we're
heading west, here.
I know that.
Well, that's not the plan.
The plan was no good.
Uh, what?
We're changing directions.
Okay. I was given
very specific orders
by the staff at the NSC.
Now, first it indicated
a chopper insertion
which we won't get into.
Then, we were supposed
to head east...
Due east.
You think Washington knows
the best way to get through
this jungle?
You think they know which
streams are flooded,
and impossible to cross?
Which trails are mined
or booby-trapped?
What I know
about this place, son
is 'cause I'm here.
Hup. Changing directions.
Good. North.
Holy shit.
What the hell
is that?
"Hotel Europa."
What kind of wacko
builds a hotel...
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Beckett...
Oh.
Sure is a hell
of a lucky break for us.
(PULLS TRIGGER)
Descargado. Descargado.
(LAUGHING)
I got ammo
and he's laughing?
(CHUCKLING)
Ease up, young agent.
They've been with us
since we left the train.
You drop the hammer on him,
we'll be dead before we even
take 10 steps.
Hola, cacique. Que tal?
Hola.
Quien es este?
El?
El es Rambo-tito.
Rambo-tito?
(LAUGHING)
Los ojos.
Quiero los ojos.
He wants my eyes?
He means  anteojos.
Your shooting glasses.
Give them to him.
Why?
Because he likes them.
Fuck him.
Look...
This area's swarming with
rebel patrols. These Indians
can help us avoid them.
Give him the glasses.
May you go blind.
(BOTH SPEAKING SPANISH)
MILLER:
Following these Indians
is fucking crazy.
Their agenda works
with ours.
Their agenda?
What agenda?
Did you see how
Cacique's hand? Did you see
the way it was cut up?
The animal who did that
is El Cirujano.
"The Surgeon."
He's headed this way
and we're gonna
take him out.
In return,
they'll lead us
past the rebel patrol.
We'll cut hours
off our time.
Our mission isn't
about assassinating
people for Indians.
El Cirujano is
listed as a target
of opportunity.
That means, we see him,
we take him out.
Where? It's not
in my orders.
Cirujano is gonna be
at this river up ahead
and Miller, you're designated
hitter on this one,
so batter up.
Wait, now hold on
a second!
I'm not buying into this.
And I don't buy
that you shot a man
from a moving helicopter.
That's got nothing
to do with anything.
You're going to look Cirujano
right in the eyes,
you're gonna put a bullet
through his fucking heart
because until I see you
kill a man, you're a
liability to this mission.
That's not
my purpose here!
Maybe, but when we get
to Alvarez's hacienda
there's gonna be
two targets.
What?
Yeah, that's right.
Intelligence changes
all the time.
Alvarez is
setting up a meeting
with a man called Raul Ochoa.
He's a Colombian drug lord
that's financing the rebels.
We got a chance
to get them both.
Where does this
information come from?
Any new intelligence
has to come through me.
A local contact,
Father Ruiz.
He's a priest
in the village of Sangre.
He'll give us specifics
on the meeting
when we get there.
BECKETT: Wind coming
off the water at 3:00.
One click right.
Make that two clicks.
MILLER:
Which one is he?
I can't tell who he is.
BECKETT:
He's the baseball fan.
He's a fucking American.
He's a fucking spook.
Ex-CIA.
I met him once
up in El Salvador.
Now he's an enforcer
for the cocaine monkeys.
I'll take out
the lieutenant.
You concentrate
on him.
Now put a fucking bullet
through his heart.
Do it.
Feel the rush.
Miller.
Breathe.
Nail that motherfucker now!
What the hell
did you just do, sniper?
I just wanted to show you
that I owned that situation.
Bullshit.
You fired a spoiler.
You saw him go down.
He's dead.
I didn't see shit!
I didn't see him hit.
For Christ's sake,
you gave him a warning shot.
I hit him.
I had him in my sights.
There's no doubt about it.
You better be right.
From now on,
one shot, one kill.
No exceptions.
You understand?
Lo siento, Cacique.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
What? Now they
blame us for this?
No.
But this sure as hell
ain't going to help us.
(MEN SPEAKING SPANISH)
(WHISPERING)
Beckett?
(MEN SPEAKING SPANISH)
(WHISPERING)
Patrol.
You really get
off on this shit,
don't you, Beckett?
Uh, it's just a job.
I don't think about it much.
So that's the secret,
not thinking.
Right.
(SIGHS) Miller...
What are you doing here?
This assignment was supposed
to be a piece of cake.
You're in, you're out
you go home and
reap the rewards.
The Washington brass
loves this shit.
Of course, they never
said anything about
a goddamn jungle creep
that's for sure.
Yeah, well,
most guys wouldn't.
Seems so far away.
What?
My life.
I read your dossier
before I came.
You had 74 confirmed kills.
It's not about numbers.
The only one
that really mattered
was the first one.
That was the toughest one
for you, right?
First one?
Yeah.
But 74, that's...
A lot of faces
to carry around.
Yeah, well...
You put them
in the back of your mind...
(CLEARING THROAT)
And you just keep on going.
That's great until
they decide not to stay
in the back of your mind.
You may find this
hard to believe
but I'll take
a nice office on the hill
over this shit any day.
Sitting in an office,
giving other
men orders to kill
ain't no different than
putting a bullet
in a man's heart.
Let me tell you something.
It's the same goddamn thing.
(GUNS FIRING IN DISTANCE)
You hear that?
An AK.
I know that
hammer recoil.
Yeah, and I think I know
who that single shot is.
He's behind us.
Who is this guy?
I think he's the guy
that killed Papich.
It ain't the first time
he's been on my trail.
He's a Panamanian
I trained.
His name is Desilva
and now he's
a fucking mercenary.
This is ridiculous.
I can't sleep here.
It's a good spot.
Stagnant.
River flukes,
leaches, malaria.
He'd never think anybody
would be stupid enough
to hide here.
Except us.
Just take
your horse pill
and don't take
a piss.
The bugs will swim
right up through
your dick.
Good night.
(GUN FIRING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(PANTING)
Tough, huh?
He's there.
And he's out of range,
damn it!
I'm looking right at the ridge
we came over.
I don't see a damn thing.
That's because
he's smarter than you.
Come over here.
Glance down to the
bottom of the finger.
Sweep up to your left
at your 11:00,
halfway.
MILLER: Got him.
Heading west.
He's lost us.
Wrong.
He's just doing
what he was trained to do.
He's circling our flank,
coming around us.
Gaining some ground.
He'll be waiting
for us somewhere.
He'll know exactly
where we are.
We have
to take him out.
Taking a break?
Mmm-hmm.
Makes it sensitive.
Marries my finger
to the trigger break.
What are you going
to do, a pedicure next?
I guess some men
are born to this work
and others aren't.
It may be your
career choice, pal,
but it ain't mine.
This career chooses a man.
Ain't the other way around.
Well, like I said,
I got other plans.
Yeah?
I had plans.
Still do.
What is it?
I'm working on
something back home.
Where you from?
Montana.
Bozeman.
Oh, shit.
I went to university there.
Miller, don't jerk me off.
I'm not in the mood.
I'm not.
Freshman and sophomore year.
I would have stayed longer
but skiing killed my grades.
Huh.
Well, I'll be damned.
You, uh, you wouldn't
happen to know
a little town
called Livingston
would you?
Sure.
Well, uh...
There's a stream nearby
up in the hills.
It's... I don't know,
three klicks east
of the interstate.
You follow that,
and you come to this, uh
rock basin, like a quarry pit,
but not as deep.
Found that when I was a kid.
Anyway, it's fed
by a tributary
of the Madisons
and it's the best
damn steelhead
fishing in the world.
I plan to go
back there, and...
I don't know,
start a little fishing camp
a guide operation, whatever.
When's the last time
you were there?
Couple years ago.
Damn it, Gunny,
a couple of years ago, they...
That whole area was levelled
seven years ago.
They got
a high school there.
Your pond is buried.
They got a tennis court
on that site.
We're not talking
about the same place.
You know we are
whether you admit it or not.
Beckett, killing's
all you got, isn't it?
What is it?
BECKETT:
Something is wrong here.
God.
What kind of...
Who would do something
like that?
I'd say the man you had
dead in your sights did this.
You don't know it
as El Cirujano.
It was probably one
of Alvarez's men.
They probably found out
what the priest was doing.
He must have
told them everything.
That means they're going
to be waiting for us.
Maybe, but if he
told them everything
why didn't they hit us here?
Hacienda's
only three klicks away.
We should make our shots
easy at dawn.
What? This mission is over.
Our contact is dead.
All we do now
is get the hell out of here.
I've never turned back
on a mission in my life
and I ain't starting now.
That's gung-ho bullshit.
Without the specifics,
it's a suicide mission.
They're all suicide missions.
I wouldn't be out here
unless I was ready to die.
Now, we've got our
location, we've got
our targets
and we've got
a time frame.
You're out
of your fucking mind.
I'm not going.
I've had enough
of your mewling.
Shut your fucking mouth!
I'm not going
with you, Beckett.
The hell you aren't.
You don't have any
choice about it.
It will never work!
We're going where
they'll never expect us.
Jarhead.
Fucking flattop lifer.
BECKETT: We camp here.
We'll make
our final approach
to the  hacienda
at dawn.
Wait a minute, okay?
Now, at the village
you said that we were
three klicks away
from the  hacienda.
Okay, now, that's
three klicks.
Now, we walking for miles.
We don't walk in
straight lines.
Now, get some sleep.
I'll take first watch.
Move out at 0400.
You can sleep here.
Argh!
Son of a bitch!
You used me as bait?
You were never really
in any danger.
(SIGHS)
BECKETT: We're about
100 yards up.
This is our rendezvous point.
If I don't show
you cross-country it
to the nearest river
follow it down stream
to the coast.
Whatever.
Hacienda , 12:00.
Most logical position would be
to take our shots
from that treeline over there
but they're gonna be
expecting that
so somehow
we got to get
in the clear
to make our shots.
When Ochoa arrives
I figure we got ten seconds
after they greet
and then we drop them
and we got to fire our shots
simultaneously
or they're gonna
vector in on
our positions.
Here's Ochoa.
He's yours.
There's a clear shot
from that metal
utilities shed
and you got
fair coverage there.
That's your position.
I'll be on the other side
of the village.
We'll both be...
Thousand yards out.
You listening, Miller?
Get below.
Miller?
There better not be any doubt
about your shot this time.
One shot, one kill.
This ain't a fucking
game out here.
You blow it, and I'll...
You'll what?
You'll kill me?
Go on, say it, Beckett.
You just get it right.
(MACHINERY RATTLING)
You son of a bitch.
(BRAKES SQUEAKING)
You lying bastard.
Fucking truck's
blocking my shot.
What are you doing?
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
(BARKING)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
(GUARDS SPEAKING SPANISH)
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
Estamos aqui.
BECKETT: Where is he?
Ah, shit, Miller.
You're out in the open.
Shit, Miller,
someone's seen you.
Flores, vengan, vengan.
(SHOUTING)
MILLER: What are you doing?
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
Argh!
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
Alvarez.
(GROANING)
Hola.
Ochoa.
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
Ten, nine...
Eight, seven...
(GRUNTING AND GROANING)
Lady, move.
(GRUNTING)
One...
One. Beckett. one.
(SCREAMING)
(GUNS FIRING)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
(MEN CHATTERING AND YELLING)
(GUN FIRING)
Ah, shit.
Did you get Ochoa?
Yes, I got Ochoa!
What happened to you?
What the hell were you
doing in that barn?
It doesn't matter.
We got to try and get back
and hit Alvarez after dark.
What, another shot?
What are you,
fucking crazy?
I got my kill!
I'm out of this mission!
There's still
two targets left...
That's because
you fucked up!
You son of a bitch!
He had the drop on you!
He had you in his cross hairs,
and I took him out!
Fuck you!
I'm not ending up on
your fucking key chain!
(GRUNTING)
(LOW, INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GUN FIRING)
Give it up, Miller!
BECKETT: You're losing it!
Pull it together!
(GUN FIRES)
Beautiful.
(GUN COCKS)
No te muevas.
(CLICKING)
(LAUGHING)
Miller.
It's over.
I'm out of bullets.
Do it.
So come on
and shoot me, already.
Do you feel the rush?
Well, I felt it.
I felt it when I had you
in my crosshairs.
After you pull
the trigger...
When the rush is over...
It hurts.
Doesn't it?
The hurt you're feeling now
ain't the worst pain.
The worst thing...
Is not feeling
the hurt anymore.
You'll get past this.
You'll get by.
Hey.
You can still go home.
(LOW, INDISTINCT
CHATTERING)
Miller...
We got to get
out of here.
I'll cover you.
No.
Son. I'm getting you
out of here. Now go.
Hey.
I'll be right
behind you.
Move it.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GROANING)
(GASPING)
(GROANS)
(JEEP APPROACHING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Tell me who you are.
Lee Harvey Oswald.
We've been
looking for you.
Hijo de puta.
You've hurt our cause.
Well, fuck you
and fuck your cause.
Es el Beckett.
Well...
All things come
to he who waits.
Right, Beckett?
Long time no see.
See if there's
any others.
Oh, Beckett and I are going
to have a long talk.
We'll hear
about everything.
(GROANS)
Amarren las manos.
Everyone back
to the  hacienda.
Vuelvan a la hacienda.
Muchacho!
Feel the trigger,
sniper.
It will be the last time.
So, where did you
leave your partner?
(SCREAMING)
Now you targeted Ochoa.
A Colombian civilian.
Is the U.S. Military
now moving against
the Colombian cartel?
(SPITS)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
Thomas Beckett,
Master Gunnery Sergeant
United States Marine Corps!
I like your dedication,
Beckett.
It's a challenge.
(GROANS)
(GASPING)
(BODY DROPS)
Wake up. Don't die
on me yet, Beckett.
I'm just starting
to have fun.
Miller.
Wait.
Wait?
Please.
One shot, two kills.
One shot... Two kills?
A man in your organization.
What?
A man...
Move.
(MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
I'm gonna go
one klick, can you make it?
Yeah.
Let's go.
One minute to rendezvous.
They better be there.
Take her down.
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
Beckett, go!
Give me that rifle.
I'll cover you.
Go on! That's an order.
Miller!
Beckett!
Let's go!
Beckett.
There's always Montana.